

### **ABOUT**

Experienced Full - Stack developer with a background in Uki Technology School, specializing in e-commerce projects, including Windows applications, web sites & databases to ensureseamless user experience. Also, skilled freelancer in UI design, SEO, and Digital Marketing

### CONTACT

- rkkumaran834@gmail.com
- © +94767710834
- Medium/kumaran
- Linkedin/kumaran
- Portfolio/kumaran

### **TOP SKILLS**

Hard Skills

HTML, CSS, bootstrap Javascript , ReactJS GitHub, Canva MongoDB , NodeJS ExpressJS , WordPress

Soft Skills
 Management Skills
 Creativity
 Team work
 Critical Thinking
 Leadership/ Planning

#### **PARTICIPATIONS**

- Yarl Geek Challenge (YGC)
   Innovation Festival 2023
   Project Name: VD-Wear
- Volunteer at YarlIT Hub (YGC)
- UI/UX Workshop at YarlIT Hub

## KANTHASUWAMY KUMARAN

### **EXPERIENCES**

Sproutgigs | Freelancer
 2022 - 2023
 Digital Marketing , Designing

Nalin Information
 Technologies (Pvt)Ltd
 2021 - 2022
 System Administrator & Technician

# SDS Computers Jan - August 2023 Hardware & Network Technician

### **PROJECTS**

VD-Wear
 Virtual-Fitting-Room Web
 Application useing Three.JS

Todo App
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 MongoDB, Node.js powered.

Movie Search HTML, CSS, JavaScript <u>Coffee Shop Web</u>
 Created using Google Sites platform

<u>Calculator</u>HTML, CSS, JavaScript

### **EDUCATIONS**

College of Technology
 Diploma in ICT
 2021 - Present (Part time)

Vocational Training
 <u>Authority</u>
 Computer Hardware & Network
 NVQ-4
 2020-2021

 J/Anai Balasupramaniya vidiyalaya
 G.C.E (O/L) Examination
 2015 (B 4C 3S)

Maths B, ICT - C, Engilsh - C

<u>Uki Technology School</u>
 Coding Accelerator Program
 2023-2024

J/Manipay Hindu College
 G.C.E (A/L) Examination
 2019 C2S
 BioTech-C, ICT-S, SFT-S

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

FreeCodeCamp
 Responsive Web Design,
 JavaScript Algorithms and
 Data Structures, Front End
 Development Libraries

Visme
 Creating Memorable Visual

 Presentations

American Corner
 Web design using HTML, CSS,
 Bootstrap

Aide et Action
 Computer Graphics Designing Photoshop , Canva

MongoDB University

M001: MongoDB Basics M121: The MongoDB Aggregation Framework M320: Data Modeling

Hacker Rank - CSS
 Enhance CSS skills & challenges
 and tutorials online

Cisco Academy
 <u>Cybersecurity</u>, <u>Internet of Things</u>,
 <u>Linux Essentials</u>, <u>Get Connected</u>

Startup Essentials Program
 Yarl Geek Challenge Innovation
 Festival (VD-Wear)

### **REFERENCES**

M Minerva Jeyarajah
 Lead Lecturer (BIT)
 Head of Uki
 Uki Technology School
 info@uki.life

Vinayagamoorthy Balalojanan Software Engineering (B.Tech) Visiting Lecturer University College Jaffna janan1992@gmail.com